Jinhang Jiang

jinhang@asu.edu | (785) 917-0782 | linkedin.com/in/jinhangjiang | jinhangjiang.github.io/My_Portfolio | Tempe, AZ 85281

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Graduate student at the W.P. Carey School of Business focusing on Business Analytics with a B.S. in Business Analytics from the University of Kansas. Experienced in text mining, manipulating large datasets, prediction modeling and deep learning.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Business Analytics at the W.P Carey School of Business Bachelor of Science in Business, Business Analytics

Arizona State University, May 2021 University of Kansas, July 2020

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

KU School of Business, Business Analytics

Lawrence, KS

Teaching Assistant - Analytics certificate program for working professionals

February 2020 - April 2020

- Partnered to teach database management concepts such as SQL, ETL, and Business Intelligence. Helped the students create a database, query the data from multiple tables, transform raw data into meaningful visualizations, and write sophisticated business reports, to further improve their knowledge of Analytical concepts
- Created supplementary tutorials in topics of Business Intelligence, such as Power BI and Tableau, to better implement into their professional lives. Some of the tutorials were selected by the professor to use as the teaching materials in the future

Research Assistant - Analytics, Information and Operations Management

- Tasked with performing natural language processing on companies' "Corporation Social Responsibility" files. Utilized R to calculate scores of Boilerplate, Redundancy, Specificity and Relative Prevalence for over 1400 CSR files. Final data is used for various sections of the analysis of a paper. Published the method of calculating Boilerplate on Towards Data Science
- Collaborated with the Professor to research predicting diseases for high-cost patients at the point of admission. Studied and analyzed over two million Electronic Health Records. Embedded adjacency matrix using the "node2vec" package in Python and plotted the results using k-means algorithm in R. Published final findings on Analytics Vidhya

China Telecom Americas Corporation

Lawrence, KS

Business Development Intern of Kansas

December 2017 - December 2019

• Promoted mobile business for the International Student Community by direct selling, customer service and data analysis. Utilize OAC and SQL to develop visualization reports. Utilized sales performance data, which was reported to the Regional Manager, with KPI's marked as "perfect" for both years

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

KU Chinese Students and Scholars Friendship Association

Lawrence, KS

President & Promotions Chair

April 2016 - May 2018

- Coordinated with International Students Services to help Chinese students integrate into the KU community
- Produced 2018 Chinese New Year Gala for over 1,500 audience members and raised \$22,000 funding
- Developed a website to market the program and published more than 30 articles online to promote Chinese cultures
- Led a team of 20 members to organize five major Chinese cultural events, cultivating awareness about Chinese traditions

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Adidas – ASU MSBA Applied Project

November 2020 – April 2021

• Tasked with implementing a full social media analytics pipeline, including data identification, data collection, data processing, text analytics, and data visualization. Outcomes of the analysis are expected to yield insights into whether the branding is effective, how it is being received by consumers, etc.

Humana-Mays Healthcare Analytics Case Competition

September 2020 – October 2020

- Captain of a team of three graduate students from ASU. Tasked with helping Humana predict and identify the customers who have trouble of transportation. Responsible for cleaning a dataset with 856 variables, comparing the statistical results and deriving business insights with Python, R and SQL. Performed hyperparameter optimization and Stacking Ensemble on LightGBM, XGBoost and CatBoost. The average performance of the final model increased roughly 10%.
- Summarized all the findings and recommendations in the final report. The final submission was ranked national top 50.

H&R Block Machine Learning Competition

October 2019 – November 2019

• Led a team of three students. Responsible for cleaning, interpreting, visualizing and explaining over a million of simulated business data from H&R Block. Identified the seasonal trends in sales both nationwide and throughout each state using SQL, analyzed service performance geographically with Power BI and Oracle Analytical Cloud, and then made predictions and recommendations for the company's business operations in the future. Received the second-place award at the University of Kansas for this competition.

AWARDS & CERTIFICATIONS

KU School of Business Dean's List for Spring 2020 H&R Block Machine Learning Competition 2nd Place at KU Certificate of Appreciation by Consul General of Consulate General of P. R. China in Chicago Jun 2020

Nov 2019

Sept 2018